Everyone knows that dogs are supposed to be our best friends.
大家都知道狗应该是我们最好的朋友。
Could it be that they know what we are thinking?
有没有可能它们知道我们在想什么呢？
Whether it's getting excited at the prospect of a walk or knowing that tasty food is coming soon, are our dogs reading our minds?
无论是一想到要去散步就兴奋，还是知道好吃的食物即将到来，我们的狗是在读心吗？
Now, by mind-reading we're not talking about knowing our deepest thoughts in detail, but various psychologists have suggested that dogs might have a theory of mind.
现在，说到读心，我们指的不是详尽了解我们最深层的想法，而是许多心理学家提出，狗可能具有心理理论。
What this means is that they are aware that other creatures, like humans, are able to see and understand things in different ways.
这意味着它们意识到其他生物（如人类）能够以不同的方式看待和理解事物。
In various experiments it appears that dogs are able to identify who is paying them attention.
在各种实验中，狗似乎能够识别谁在关注它们。
They are more likely to ask for food from someone if there is a reason that the human would know where the dog treats are.
如果狗能判断出谁会知道零食在哪里，狗就更有可能向那个人讨要食物。
If dogs have been forbidden food by someone, they are more likely to try and get it quietly.
如果狗被某人禁止吃食物，它们就更有可能试图悄悄地得到它。
As well as these behavioural studies, there are other things that show how dogs are able to relate closely to humans.
除了这些行为研究，还有其他事情表明狗能够与人类建立密切联系。
Brain imaging studies have shown not only that canine brains react to human voices, but that they also show an emotional response to those human sounds which demonstrate strong feelings, such as laughing or crying.
脑成像研究表明，不仅狗的大脑对人类的声音有反应，而且它们对表现出强烈情感（如大笑或哭泣）的人类声音也会产生情绪反应。
Brain scan studies have also shown that human faces also provoke an emotional response in dogs.
脑部扫描研究还表明，人类面孔也会引起狗的情绪反应。
Other studies have shown that sweat from people feeling scared could make dogs feel more stressed than sweat from happy people.
其他研究表明，感到恐惧的人的汗水比感到愉快的人的汗水更能让狗感到压力。
There is some debate about whether dogs have evolved to respond to human emotions as they have become domesticated or whether this behaviour is a learned reaction to stimuli.
关于狗是随着被驯化而进化出对人类情绪的反应，还是这种行为是对刺激的后天习得反应，存在一些争论。
Experiments like those described above have also been carried out on wolves that have been raised by humans, who may have learned to respond to their carer's behaviour, but do not have the genes of a domesticated species.
上述类似的实验也对由人类抚养长大的狼进行过，这些狼可能学会了回应照顾者的行为，但它们不具有驯化物种的基因。
Wolves did show some abilities to respond to human emotions, but were less able to pick up more subtle clues.
狼确实表现出一些回应人类情绪的能力，但不太能够捕捉更细微的线索。
Whether it's learned or innate, dogs' ability to read human emotions and intentions are one reason that we have included them in our lives for centuries.
无论是习得的还是天生的，狗解读人类情绪和意图的能力是我们几个世纪以来让它们进入我们生活的原因之一。
It's also why they have been successful as assistance dogs, helping their owners to get through everyday life.
这也是它们作为辅助犬成功帮助主人度过日常生活的原因。